<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<catalog name="Ensemble Dressing of North American Land Data Assimilation version 2 (EDN2)" xmlns="http://www.unidata.ucar.edu/namespaces/thredds/InvCatalog/v1.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <!--Top level dataset: Needed to set metadata for Files & Aggregations-->
  <dataset name="Ensemble Dressing of North American Land Data Assimilation version 2 (EDN2)">
    <metadata inherited="true">
      <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      <dataFormat>NetCDF</dataFormat>
      <dataType>GRID</dataType>
      <documentation type="Rights">Freely Available</documentation>
      <documentation xlink:href="http://rda.ucar.edu/datasets/ds613.0/" xlink:title="NCAR RDA - Ensemble Dressing of North American Land Data Assimilation version 2 (EDN2)(ds613.0)" />
      <documentation type="summary">Most datasets of surface meteorology are deterministic, yet many applications using these datasets require or can benefit from uncertainty estimates in meteorological fields. Motivated by this gap, we applied a locally-weighted spatial regression technique with the widely-used North American Land Data Assimilation version 2 (NLDAS-2) dataset values to generate ensemble estimates for daily precipitation, daily mean temperature, and diurnal temperature range. The approach is a form of ensemble dressing. This uncertainty dataset and methods from this work are made publicly available to support research such a data assimilation or model uncertainty studies.
    The dataset includes a 100-member ensemble for daily precipitation, temperature and diurnal temperature range at 1/8th degree for the NLDAS-2 domain (25 to 53 North, 125 to 67 West), for the time period 1979-2019. It also includes the spatial regression coefficients and other inputs needed to run the Gridded Meteorological Ensemble Tool (GMET) used to generate the ensembles. A limited number of summary statistical analyses of the dataset are also included.</documentation>
      <creator>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">UCAR/NCAR/CGD</name>
        <contact url="none" />
      </creator>
      <creator>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">UCAR/NCAR/RAL/HAP</name>
        <contact url="none" />
      </creator>
      <creator>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">USASK/HYDROLOGY</name>
        <contact url="none" />
      </creator>
      <authority>edu.ucar.rda</authority>
      <publisher>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">NCAR/RDA</name>
        <contact email="rdahelp@ucar.edu" url="http://rda.ucar.edu/" />
    </publisher>
    </metadata>
    <!--Files-->
    <datasetScan location="/data/rda/data/ds613.0/" name="613.0 Files" path="files/g/ds613.0">
      <metadata inherited="true">
        <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      </metadata>
      <filter>
        <exclude wildcard="*.html" />
      </filter>
      <addDatasetSize />
    </datasetScan>
  </dataset>
</catalog>
