<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<catalog name="NOAA NCEI Extended Reconstructed Sea Surface Temperature" xmlns="http://www.unidata.ucar.edu/namespaces/thredds/InvCatalog/v1.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <!--Top level dataset: Needed to set metadata for Files & Aggregations-->
  <dataset name="NOAA NCEI Extended Reconstructed Sea Surface Temperature">
    <metadata inherited="true">
      <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      <dataFormat>NetCDF</dataFormat>
      <dataType>GRID</dataType>
      <documentation type="Rights">Freely Available</documentation>
      <documentation xlink:href="http://rda.ucar.edu/datasets/d277009/" xlink:title="NCAR RDA - NOAA NCEI Extended Reconstructed Sea Surface Temperature(d277009)" />
      <documentation type="summary">
    The NOAA NCEI (National Center for Environmental Information) Extended Reconstructed Sea Surface Temperature (ERSST) dataset is a global monthly sea surface temperature dataset derived from the International Comprehensive Ocean-Atmosphere Dataset (ICOADS). Production of the ERSST is on a 2 degree grid with spatial completeness enhanced using statistical methods. This monthly analysis begins in January 1854 continuing to the present and includes anomalies computed with respect to a 1971-2000 monthly climatology. The newest version of ERSST, version 5, uses new data sets from ICOADS Release 3.0 (Sea Surface Temperatures) SST; SST comes from Argo floats above 5 meters, Hadley Centre sea ice and SST version 2 (HadISST.2) ice concentration. ERSSTv5 has improved SST spatial and temporal variability by
    
    reducing spatial filtering in training the reconstruction functions Empirical Orthogonal Teleconnections (EOTs),
    removing high-latitude damping in EOTs,
    adding 10 more EOTs in the Arctic.
    
    ERSSTv5 improved absolute SST by switching from using Nighttime Marine Air Temperature (NMAT) as a reference to buoy SST as a reference in correcting ship SST biases. Scientists have further improved ERSSTv5 by using unadjusted First-Guess instead of adjusted First-Guess.
    </documentation>
      <creator>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">DOC/NOAA/NESDIS/NCEI</name>
        <contact url="none" />
      </creator>
      <authority>edu.ucar.rda</authority>
      <publisher>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">NCAR/RDA</name>
        <contact email="rdahelp@ucar.edu" url="http://rda.ucar.edu/" />
    </publisher>
    </metadata>
    <!--Files-->
    <datasetScan location="/data/rda/data/d277009/ersst.v5.nc" name="277.9 Files" path="files/g/d277009">
      <metadata inherited="true">
        <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      </metadata>
      <filter>
        <exclude wildcard="*.html" />
      </filter>
      <addDatasetSize />
    </datasetScan>
  </dataset>
</catalog>

