<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<catalog name="Atmospheric River Tracking Method Intercomparison Project Tier 2 CMIP5/6 Source Data and Catalogues" xmlns="http://www.unidata.ucar.edu/namespaces/thredds/InvCatalog/v1.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <!--Top level dataset: Needed to set metadata for Files & Aggregations-->
  <dataset name="Atmospheric River Tracking Method Intercomparison Project Tier 2 CMIP5/6 Source Data and Catalogues">
    <metadata inherited="true">
      <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      <dataFormat>NetCDF</dataFormat>
      <dataType>GRID</dataType>
      <documentation type="Rights">Freely Available</documentation>
      <documentation xlink:href="http://gdex.ucar.edu/datasets/d651016/" xlink:title="NCAR GDEX - Atmospheric River Tracking Method Intercomparison Project Tier 2 CMIP5/6 Source Data and Catalogues(d651016)" />
      <documentation type="summary">Atmospheric River Tracking Method Intercomparison Project (ARTMIP) Tier 2 CMIP5/6 developer catalogues and source data. Each ARTMIP method/algorithm (named by developer) submits a catalogue comprised of 0's (no AR exists) or 1's (yes AR exists) for each time slice, for each grid point, using a curated set of output from the Coupled Model Intercomparison Project 5 and 6 multi-model ensembles (see Table 1). Catalogues are created for single ensemble members from historical simulations and for RCP8.5 (CMIP5) and SSP5-8.5 (CMIP6) future simulations, for the 1950-2099 time period. Ensemble member r1i1p1f1 or r1i1p1f1 is used for each input, with the exception of the CMIP5 CCSM4 run, which uses ensemble member r6i1p1. Derived CMIP5/6 quantities required for algorithms, such as IVT or IWV, were computed by the ARTMIP project so that all methods use the exact same data.
    There are some exceptions to the time period noted above: output from the CMIP6 IPSL-CM6A-LR SSP5-8.5 simulation are only available through 2049, there are data corruption issues for the year 2006 in the CMIP5 CSIRO-Mk3-6-0 simulation, and there are data corruption issues for the year 2095-2099 for the TECA_BARD_v1.0 output applied to the CMIP5 IPSL-CM5B-LR simulation. The Guan_Waliser_v2 algorithm did not supply ARDT catalogues for the NorESM1-M and BCC-CSM2-MR simulations. </documentation>
      <creator>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">UCAR/NCAR/CGD</name>
        <contact url="none" />
      </creator>
      <authority>edu.ucar.gdex</authority>
      <publisher>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">NCAR/GDEX</name>
        <contact url="http://gdex.ucar.edu/" email="datahelp@ucar.edu" />
    </publisher>
    </metadata>
    <!--Files-->
    <datasetScan name="d651016 Files" path="files/d651016" location="/data/rda/data/d651016/">
      <metadata inherited="true">
        <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      </metadata>
      <filter>
        <exclude wildcard="*.html" />
        <exclude wildcard="*.x" />
        <exclude wildcard=".*" />
        <exclude wildcard=".*/" />
      </filter>
      <addDatasetSize />
    </datasetScan>
  </dataset>
</catalog>
