<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<catalog name="ERA5.1: Corrections to ERA5 Stratospheric Temperature 2000-2006" xmlns="http://www.unidata.ucar.edu/namespaces/thredds/InvCatalog/v1.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <!--Top level dataset: Needed to set metadata for Files & Aggregations-->
  <dataset name="ERA5.1: Corrections to ERA5 Stratospheric Temperature 2000-2006">
    <metadata inherited="true">
      <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      <dataFormat>GRIB-1</dataFormat>
      <dataType>GRID</dataType>
      <documentation type="Rights">Freely Available</documentation>
      <documentation xlink:href="http://gdex.ucar.edu/datasets/d633002/" xlink:title="NCAR GDEX - ERA5.1: Corrections to ERA5 Stratospheric Temperature 2000-2006(d633002)" />
      <documentation type="summary">In ECMWF Technical Memo 859 released in January 2020, Simmons and his coauthors
    report that "the ERA5 analyses of lower stratospheric temperature exhibit a
    pronounced cold bias for the years 2000 to 2006. This is due to specifying
    background error covariances for the data assimilation that were inappropriate
    prior to availability during 2006 of GNSS radio occultation data in sufficient
    numbers to constrain a cold bias of the assimilating ERA5 model. A new set of
    analyses, termed ERA5.1, has thus been produced for the period from 2000 to
    2006 using the background error covariances that were used to produce the
    ERA5 analyses for the years 1979 to 1999. ERA5.1 also includes the more
    restrictive ensemble assimilation of SBUV ozone data that was used in production
    of ERA5 for 1979 to 1999."
    
    "ERA5.1 provides analyses with better global-mean temperatures in the
    stratosphere and uppermost troposphere than provided by ERA5. ERA5.1 stands up
    well in comparison with ERA-Interim and other reanalyses in the lower stratosphere,
    although there are also lower-stratospheric temperature differences between ERA5
    and other reanalyses in the 1980s and 1990s. These are due in part to differences
    in radiosonde temperature bias adjustment. The pronounced near-tropopause cold bias
    of ERA5 from 2000 to 2006 has implications for the representation of stratospheric
    humidity, for which ERA5.1 performs better, though by no means perfectly.
    ERA5.1 does not exhibit the  spuriously high values of ozone that occur close
    to the South Pole in the polar nights of 2003 and 2004 in the ERA5 analyses.
    Synoptic evolution in the extratropical stratosphere is seen to be
    very similar in two cases involving splitting of the stratospheric polar vortex and
    secondary vortex formation by dynamical instability. The ERA5.1 representation of
    the QBO agrees slightly better with radiosonde wind data than that of ERA5.
    The dataset formed by merging ERA5.1 with ERA5 is generally more homogeneous
    over time than ERA5 alone. It nevertheless is problematic for global-mean upper
    stratospheric temperature for all but the most recent ten or so years."
    
    "ERA5.1 is very close to ERA5 in the lower and middle troposphere."</documentation>
      <creator>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">ECMWF</name>
        <contact url="none" />
      </creator>
      <authority>edu.ucar.gdex</authority>
      <publisher>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">NCAR/GDEX</name>
        <contact url="http://gdex.ucar.edu/" email="datahelp@ucar.edu" />
    </publisher>
    </metadata>
    <!--Files-->
    <datasetScan name="d633002 Files" path="files/d633002" location="/data/rda/data/d633002/">
      <metadata inherited="true">
        <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      </metadata>
      <filter>
        <exclude wildcard="*.html" />
        <exclude wildcard="*.x" />
        <exclude wildcard=".*" />
        <exclude wildcard=".*/" />
      </filter>
      <addDatasetSize />
    </datasetScan>
  </dataset>
</catalog>
