<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<catalog name="Simulation of the Transient Climate of the Last 21,000 Years (TraCE-21ka)" xmlns="http://www.unidata.ucar.edu/namespaces/thredds/InvCatalog/v1.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <!--Top level dataset: Needed to set metadata for Files & Aggregations-->
  <dataset name="Simulation of the Transient Climate of the Last 21,000 Years (TraCE-21ka)">
    <metadata inherited="true">
      <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      <dataFormat>NetCDF</dataFormat>
      <dataType>GRID</dataType>
      <documentation type="Rights">Freely Available</documentation>
      <documentation xlink:href="http://gdex.ucar.edu/datasets/d651050/" xlink:title="NCAR GDEX - Simulation of the Transient Climate of the Last 21,000 Years (TraCE-21ka)(d651050)" />
      <documentation type="summary">This TraCE-21ka dataset contains output from the full TraCE simulation from 22,000 years before present (22ka) to 1990 CE as well as single-forcing sensitivity simulations of varying lengths. These results are from a fully-coupled, non-accelerated atmosphere-ocean-sea ice-land surface CCSM3 simulation at the T31_gx3 resolution. For the full TraCE simulation, the model is forced with transient greenhouse gas concentrations and orbitally-driven insolation changes. Transient boundary conditions include the ICE-5G ice sheets - extent and topography, and changing paleogeography as sea level rises from its Last Glacial Maximum low stand to modern levels. We also prescribe a transient scenario of meltwater forcing to the oceans from the retreating ice sheets. Vegetation is prognostic.
The following CCSM3 simulations are available:
[TraCE] full TraCE simulation, with transient forcing changes in greenhouse gases, orbitally-driven insolation variations, ice sheets and meltwater fluxes.
[TraCE-ORB] with only transient orbital forcing, all other forcings and boundary conditions remain at the full TraCE state of 22ka.
[TraCE-GHG] with only transient greenhouse gas forcing, all other forcings and boundary conditions remain at the full TraCE state of 22ka.
[TraCE-ICE] with only changing continental ice sheets, all other forcings and boundary conditions remain at the full TraCE state of 19ka.
[TraCE-MWF] with only transient Northern Hemisphere meltwater fluxes, all other forcings and boundary conditions remain at the full TraCE state of 19ka.
[TraCE-ORB-17ka] with only transient orbital forcing, all other forcings and boundary conditions remain at the full TraCE state of 17ka.
[TraCE-GHG-17ka] with only transient greenhouse gas forcing, all other forcings and boundary conditions remain at the full TraCE state of 17ka. </documentation>
      <creator>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">UCAR/NCAR/CGD</name>
        <contact url="none" />
      </creator>
      <authority>edu.ucar.gdex</authority>
      <publisher>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">NCAR/GDEX</name>
        <contact url="http://gdex.ucar.edu/" email="datahelp@ucar.edu" />
    </publisher>
    </metadata>
    <!--Files-->
    <datasetScan name="d651050 Files" path="files/d651050" location="/data/rda/data/d651050/">
      <metadata inherited="true">
        <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      </metadata>
      <filter>
        <exclude wildcard="*.html" />
        <exclude wildcard="*.x" />
        <exclude wildcard=".*" />
        <exclude wildcard=".*/" />
      </filter>
      <addDatasetSize />
    </datasetScan>
  </dataset>
</catalog>
