<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<catalog name="ERA5 Modes of Interannual Variability" xmlns="http://www.unidata.ucar.edu/namespaces/thredds/InvCatalog/v1.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <!--Top level dataset: Needed to set metadata for Files & Aggregations-->
  <dataset name="ERA5 Modes of Interannual Variability">
    <metadata inherited="true">
      <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      <dataFormat>NetCDF</dataFormat>
      <dataType>GRID</dataType>
      <documentation type="Rights">Freely Available</documentation>
      <documentation xlink:href="http://rda.ucar.edu/datasets/d633003/" xlink:title="NCAR RDA - ERA5 Modes of Interannual Variability(d633003)" />
      <documentation type="summary">This dataset represents a suite of climate diagnostics for 56 variables relating to the interannual variability of ECMWF ERA5 monthly mean data. Basic fields for each of these variables include a monthly mean climatology and standard deviation, corresponding anomalies  spanning 40 or more years of data, empirical orthogonal
    functions (EOFs),  principal component (PC) time series, percent variance
    explained by each EOF, and an estimate of the standard error of the percent
    variance explained. Dominant modes of variability include El Nino Southern
    Oscillation (ENSO) in sea surface temperature, and the Antarctic Oscillation
    (AO) and North Atlantic Oscillation (NAO) in surface pressure. Separate analyses
    are performed for the entire globe, northern hemisphere only, and southern hemisphere
    only.  There is sufficient information to further explore lagged correlations, teleconnections, and more advanced statistical techniques. Preparation and calculation of this dataset is performed by CISL DECS at NCAR.</documentation>
      <creator>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">ECMWF</name>
        <contact url="none" />
      </creator>
      <authority>edu.ucar.rda</authority>
      <publisher>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">NCAR/RDA</name>
        <contact email="rdahelp@ucar.edu" url="http://rda.ucar.edu/" />
      </publisher>
      <keyword>ERA5</keyword>
      <keyword>ECWMF ERA5 Reanalysis</keyword>
    </metadata>
    <!--Files-->
    <datasetScan location="/data/rda/data/d633003/" name="633.3 Files" path="files/g/d633003">
      <metadata inherited="true">
        <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      </metadata>
      <filter>
        <exclude wildcard="*.html" />
      </filter>
      <addDatasetSize />
    </datasetScan>
  </dataset>
</catalog>

