<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<catalog name="ERA5-Land hourly data from 1950 to present (GDEX Subset)" xmlns="http://www.unidata.ucar.edu/namespaces/thredds/InvCatalog/v1.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <!--Top level dataset: Needed to set metadata for Files & Aggregations-->
  <dataset name="ERA5-Land hourly data from 1950 to present (GDEX Subset)">
    <metadata inherited="true">
      <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      <dataFormat>NetCDF</dataFormat>
      <dataType>GRID</dataType>
      <documentation type="Rights">Freely Available</documentation>
      <documentation xlink:href="http://gdex.ucar.edu/datasets/d633008/" xlink:title="NCAR GDEX - ERA5-Land hourly data from 1950 to present (GDEX Subset)(d633008)" />
      <documentation type="summary">ERA5-Land is a replay of the land component of the ERA5 climate reanalysis, forced by meteorological fields from ERA5. Note that ERA5-Land was forced by the ERA5 Preliminary back extension, rather than by the final ERA5 back extension for data older than 1979. ERA5-Land uses forcing fields based on the final release of ERA5 (i.e., expver=0001) for data after 1978. ERA5-Land comes with a series of improvements making it more accurate for all types of land applications. In particular, ERA5-Land runs at enhanced resolution (9 km versus 31 km in ERA5). The temporal frequency of the output is hourly and the fields are masked for all oceans, making them lighter to handle. 
ERA5-Land is produced under a single simulation, without coupling to the atmospheric module of the ECMWF's Integrated Forecasting System (IFS) or to the ocean wave model of the IFS. It runs without data assimilation, making it computationally affordable for relatively quick updates. For example, if significant improvements of the land surface model are implemented, the whole or part of the dataset can be reprocessed in a relatively short period. Also, updates are possible in case improved auxiliary datasets are used as input for the production.
Observations indirectly influence the simulation through the atmospheric forcing of ERA5. This forcing drives the ERA5-Land single simulation and it has been obtained by assimilating observations through a 4D-VAR data assimilation system and a Simplified Extended Kalman Filter.
The core of ERA5-Land is the Tiled ECMWF Scheme for Surface Exchanges over Land incorporating land surface hydrology (H-TESSEL). It uses version CY45R1 of the IFS.</documentation>
      <creator>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">ECMWF</name>
        <contact url="none" />
      </creator>
      <authority>edu.ucar.gdex</authority>
      <publisher>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">NCAR/GDEX</name>
        <contact url="http://gdex.ucar.edu/" email="datahelp@ucar.edu" />
      </publisher>
      <keyword>ERA5</keyword>
      <keyword>ECWMF ERA5 Reanalysis</keyword>
    </metadata>
    <!--Files-->
    <datasetScan name="d633008 Files" path="files/d633008" location="/data/rda/data/d633008/">
      <metadata inherited="true">
        <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      </metadata>
      <filter>
        <exclude wildcard="*.html" />
        <exclude wildcard="*.x" />
        <exclude wildcard=".*" />
        <exclude wildcard=".*/" />
      </filter>
      <addDatasetSize />
    </datasetScan>
  </dataset>
</catalog>
