<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<catalog name="ERA40 T85 Monthly Mean Surface Analysis and Surface Forecast Fields, created at NCAR" xmlns="http://www.unidata.ucar.edu/namespaces/thredds/InvCatalog/v1.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <!--Top level dataset: Needed to set metadata for Files & Aggregations-->
  <dataset name="ERA40 T85 Monthly Mean Surface Analysis and Surface Forecast Fields, created at NCAR">
    <metadata inherited="true">
      <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      <dataFormat>GRIB-1</dataFormat>
      <dataType>GRID</dataType>
      <documentation type="Rights">Freely Available</documentation>
      <documentation xlink:href="http://gdex.ucar.edu/datasets/d126000/" xlink:title="NCAR GDEX - ERA40 T85 Monthly Mean Surface Analysis and Surface Forecast Fields, created at NCAR(d126000)" />
      <documentation type="summary">DS126.0 represents a dataset implemented and computed by NCAR's Data Support Section, and forms an essential
    part of efforts undertaken in late 2004, early 2005, to produce an archive of selected segments of ERA-40 on a
    standard transformation grid.
    
    In this case, forty seven ERA-40 monthly mean surface and single level analysis
    variables were transformed from a reduced N80 Gaussian grid to a 256 by 128 regular Gaussian grid. All fields were
    transformed using routines from the ECMWF EMOS library, including 10 meter winds which were treated as scalars
    because of a lack of 10 meter spectral vorticity and divergence. A missing value occurs in the sea
    surface temperature and sea ice fields to mask grid points occurring over land. Fields formerly
    archived as whole integers, such as vegetation indices and cloud cover, occur as integers plus a fractional part
    in the T85 version due to interpolation.
    
    Twenty seven ERA-40 monthly mean surface and single level 6-hour forecast
    variables were transformed from a reduced N80 Gaussian grid to a 256 by 128 regular Gaussian grid.
    Four of the variables are "instantaneous" variables, and the remaining twenty three variables
    are "accumulated" over the 6-hour forecast time. Divide the accumulated variables by 21600 seconds to obtain
    instantaneous values. (Multiplication by minus one may also be necessary to match the sign convention one is
    accustomed to.)  All fields were transformed using routines from the ECMWF EMOS library, including three
    pairs of stresses which were treated as scalars because of a lack of spectral precursors.
    
    In addition, all corresponding 00Z, 06Z, 12Z, and 18Z monthly mean surface and single level analysis variables
    and 6-hour forecast variables
    were also transformed to a T85 Gaussian grid.
    
    All forecast variables are valid 6 hours after the forecast was initiated. Thus, 00Z 6-hour forecast evaporation
    is valid at 06Z.  Divide the accumulated variables by 21600 seconds to obtain instantaneous values.
    (Multiplication by minus one may also be necessary to match the sign convention one is to.)
    
    
    The choice of a
    T85 Gaussian grid was based on considerations of limiting the volume of new data generated to a moderate level,
    and to match the horizontal resolution of the
    Community Atmosphere Model (CAM) component of
    NCAR's Community Climate System Model (CCSM).
    The ERA-Interim data from ECMWF is an update to the ERA-40 project.  The ERA-Interim data starts in 1989 and has a higher horizontal resolution (T255, N128 nominally 0.703125 degrees) than the ERA-40 data (T159, N80 nominally  1.125 degrees).  ERA-Interim is based on a more current model than ERA-40 and uses 4DVAR (as opposed to 3DVAR in ERA-40).  ECMWF will continue to run the ERA-Interim model in near real time through at least 2010, and possibly longer.  This data is available in ds627.0. </documentation>
      <creator>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">UCAR/NCAR/CISL/RDA</name>
        <contact url="none" />
      </creator>
      <creator>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">ECMWF</name>
        <contact url="none" />
      </creator>
      <authority>edu.ucar.gdex</authority>
      <publisher>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">NCAR/GDEX</name>
        <contact url="http://gdex.ucar.edu/" email="datahelp@ucar.edu" />
      </publisher>
      <keyword>ERA40</keyword>
      <keyword>ECMWF ERA40 Reanalysis Project</keyword>
    </metadata>
    <!--Files-->
    <datasetScan name="d126000 Files" path="files/d126000" location="/data/rda/data/d126000/">
      <metadata inherited="true">
        <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      </metadata>
      <filter>
        <exclude wildcard="*.html" />
        <exclude wildcard="*.x" />
        <exclude wildcard=".*" />
        <exclude wildcard=".*/" />
      </filter>
      <addDatasetSize />
    </datasetScan>
  </dataset>
</catalog>
