<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<catalog name="JRA-55: Japanese 55-year Reanalysis, Near Real-Time Data -- Monthly Means and Variances" xmlns="http://www.unidata.ucar.edu/namespaces/thredds/InvCatalog/v1.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <!--Top level dataset: Needed to set metadata for Files & Aggregations-->
  <dataset name="JRA-55: Japanese 55-year Reanalysis, Near Real-Time Data -- Monthly Means and Variances">
    <metadata inherited="true">
      <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      <dataFormat>GRIB-1</dataFormat>
      <dataType>GRID</dataType>
      <documentation type="Rights">Freely Available</documentation>
      <documentation xlink:href="http://gdex.ucar.edu/datasets/d628009/" xlink:title="NCAR GDEX - JRA-55: Japanese 55-year Reanalysis, Near Real-Time Data -- Monthly Means and Variances(d628009)" />
      <documentation type="summary">The Japan Meteorological Agency (JMA) conducted JRA-55, the second Japanese global atmospheric reanalysis project. It covers 55 years, extending back to 1958, coinciding with the establishment of the global radiosonde observing system. Compared to its predecessor, JRA-25, JRA-55 is based on a new data assimilation and prediction system (DA) that improves many deficiencies found in the first Japanese reanalysis. These improvements have come about by implementing higher spatial resolution (TL319L60), a new radiation scheme, four-dimensional variational data assimilation (4D-Var) with Variational Bias Correction (VarBC) for satellite radiances, and introduction of greenhouse gases with time varying concentrations. The entire JRA-55 production was completed in 2013, and thereafter will be continued on a real time basis.
    Specific early results of quality assessment of JRA-55 indicate that a large temperature bias in the lower stratosphere has been significantly reduced compared to JRA-25 through a combination of the new radiation scheme and application of VarBC (which also reduces unrealistic temperature variations). In addition, a dry land surface anomaly in the Amazon basin has been mitigated, and overall forecast scores are much improved over JRA-25.
    Most of the observational data employed in JRA-55 are those used in JRA-25. Additionally, newly reprocessed METEOSAT and GMS data were supplied by EUMETSAT and MSC/JMA respectively. Snow depth data over the United States, Russia and Mongolia were supplied by UCAR, RIHMI and IMH respectively.</documentation>
      <creator>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">JP/JMA</name>
        <contact url="none" />
      </creator>
      <authority>edu.ucar.gdex</authority>
      <publisher>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">NCAR/GDEX</name>
        <contact url="http://gdex.ucar.edu/" email="datahelp@ucar.edu" />
    </publisher>
    </metadata>
    <!--Files-->
    <datasetScan name="d628009 Files" path="files/d628009" location="/data/rda/data/d628009/">
      <metadata inherited="true">
        <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      </metadata>
      <filter>
        <exclude wildcard="*.html" />
        <exclude wildcard="*.x" />
        <exclude wildcard=".*" />
        <exclude wildcard=".*/" />
      </filter>
      <addDatasetSize />
    </datasetScan>
  </dataset>
</catalog>
