<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<catalog name="NCEP FNL Operational Model Global Tropospheric Analyses, July 1976 to April 1997" xmlns="http://www.unidata.ucar.edu/namespaces/thredds/InvCatalog/v1.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
  <!--Top level dataset: Needed to set metadata for Files & Aggregations-->
  <dataset name="NCEP FNL Operational Model Global Tropospheric Analyses, July 1976 to April 1997">
    <metadata inherited="true">
      <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      <dataFormat>NetCDF</dataFormat>
      <dataType>GRID</dataType>
      <documentation type="Rights">Freely Available</documentation>
      <documentation xlink:href="http://gdex.ucar.edu/datasets/d082000/" xlink:title="NCAR GDEX - NCEP FNL Operational Model Global Tropospheric Analyses, July 1976 to April 1997(d082000)" />
      <documentation type="summary">
    The Final (FNL) global tropospheric analyses archived here were produced by NCEP's Global Forecast System (GFS), which was run operationally at 12-hour intervals to make multiple-day weather forecasts, from July 1976 through mid-April 1997.  FNLs are analyses that are produced after the model has completed the forecast cycle, and they include the most complete set of observations available for a given cycle.  The FNL from a given cycle, which is the best available analysis, is then used in the initialization of the next cycle.
    
    
    FNL Data are available on pairs of 2.5-degree hemispheric grids (North and South) at the Earth's surface, twelve vertical levels from 1000 millibars up to 50 millibars, the tropopause, boundary and some sigma layers, and a few other levels.  Parameters include surface pressure, sea level pressure, geopotential height, temperature, sea surface temperature, potential temperature, relative humidity, snow depth (weekly, Northern Hemisphere only) precipitable water, u- and v- winds, and vertical motion.
    </documentation>
      <creator>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">DOC/NOAA/NWS/NCEP</name>
        <contact url="none" />
      </creator>
      <authority>edu.ucar.gdex</authority>
      <publisher>
        <name vocabulary="DIF">NCAR/GDEX</name>
        <contact url="http://gdex.ucar.edu/" email="datahelp@ucar.edu" />
    </publisher>
    </metadata>
    <!--Files-->
    <datasetScan name="d082000 Files" path="files/d082000" location="/data/rda/data/d082000/">
      <metadata inherited="true">
        <serviceName>all</serviceName>
      </metadata>
      <filter>
        <exclude wildcard="*.html" />
        <exclude wildcard="*.x" />
        <exclude wildcard=".*" />
        <exclude wildcard=".*/" />
      </filter>
      <addDatasetSize />
    </datasetScan>
  </dataset>
</catalog>
